迈克:你非要发出这种怪声吗?
Mike: Ben, do you have to suck you cereal like that?
本:不.
Ben: No.
杰森:本把嘴靠到碗边喝汤!
Jason: Ben, don't drink out of a bowl.
本:这是迈克的主意.
Ben: It was Mike's idea.
杰森:赶紧吃饭,我们还有好多家务事要做.
Jason: We have to finish the breakfast soon.We have a lot of chores to
do today
迈克:爸爸,今天可是星期六,
Mike: Dad, it's Saturday,
平时上课这么累,你就不能让我放松一下吗?
when today is my date on one of all the hard work from in school.
杰森:好的,那就请你帮帮我和本怎么样?
Jason: Well, it hurt you to help me and little Ben?
本:对不起,爸爸,今天我没空.
Ben: Sorry, Dad, I am tied up today.
杰森:什么啊?
Jason: Excuse me?
本:你老是让我要好好利用时间,
Ben: You always say I should make better use of my time,
所以我就画了一个计划表.
so I drew up a schedule.
杰森:本·西沃的星期六安排:上午看动画片,中午吃午饭,
Jason: Ben Seaver, Saturday morning: watch Cartoon; noon time: eat lunch;
下午玩电子游戏机,傍晚吃点心.
afternoon: play Video games; late afternoon: light snack.
本:安排都挺轻松的吧!
Ben: Nothing heavy.
迈克:既然本今天也没什么事,
Mike: since Ben has absolutely nothing to do you can say,
就让他帮你做家务事好了.
then he can help you with the chores.
杰森:那你今天又有什么计划呢?
Jason: then what exactly do you ever plan?
迈克:嗯,我本不想告诉你的,
Mike: um...Well, I wasn't going to tell you dad, I guess I have to.
但看来还是告诉你吧,我要带几个孤儿去吃汉堡包.
I'm taking some orphans out for burgers.
杰森:算了吧!迈克.
Jason: Forget it, Mike.
迈克:哦,好吧,好吧!就让那些孤儿伤心吧!
Mike: Oh, fine, fine, just break the little kids' hearts.
杰森:好吧,
Jason: All right, well, we can begin with the not favorite,
我们就从这有些烦人的车库开始打扫吧.
scrubbing out the garage.
本:迈克,我才不会给孤儿买汉堡包.
Ben: Even I didn't buy the orphan bid, Mike.
开萝尔:嘿!
Carol: Hi.
杰森:开萝尔,早上好,今天你看上去真漂亮.
Jason: well, Good morning, Carol, don't you look sheik today.
开萝尔:谢谢.
Carol: Thanks.
迈克:你这身打扮刚好适合打扫车库.
Mike: Hey, just perfect for helping out the garage today.
开萝尔:啊,我也很想干,但是这种事我不会做.
Carol: ah, I love to do my share, but the thing is I cannot.
迈克:爸爸,你去还是我去教训一下开萝尔?
Mike: Well, dad, do you want to have her a lesson or shall I?
杰森:开萝尔,今天我们要做一些家务事.
Jason: well, we do have to do our job around house today, Carol.
开萝尔:爸爸,我也很想干,
Carol: Dad, I'd love to do my share,
但问题是她说要是不一起出去走走我们都快成陌生人了,
but the thing is Mom is in wonderful moods where she says for turning
所以她今天一天都计划好了:购物,
into strangers.So she has a whole day planned, shopping,
吃午饭,做发型
lunch and even a visit to her hair salon.
杰森:开萝尔,但今天可是西沃的家庭劳动日.
Jason: But today is a scheduled Seavor chore day, Carol.
开萝尔:你动员迈克和本做家务,要是妈妈看见她肯定会很高兴的.
Carol: well, Mom got inspired from watching you bounce with Mike and Ben.
杰森:谢谢,你们的安排蛮好的.
Jason: Well, thank you.Now, that's good,
迈克:蛮好,那就好了?你就这样让开萝尔逃掉了!
Mike: Good, that's it?You get carol off all the junk work.
迈克:迈克,
Jason: Mike, I think it is a very important opportunity here for your
让开萝尔和你妈妈一起出去玩玩,
sister and your mother just to spend some fun time to get bonding;
这是她们联络感情和改善关系的好机会.
it's good for their relationship.
本:难道就不能在这粘乎乎的车库了联络感情吗?
Ben: Can't be bonded while scrubbing the greasy things in the garage?
开萝尔:你讲得很对,对我是不太公平,
Carol: You are right; it's unfair if up to me.
我也想在这儿和大家干,可又怎么能让妈妈伤心呢?
I'll be here slaving away with guys, but how can I break mom's heart, right?
麦琪:早上好,快穿上你的外套,
Maggie: Good morning.Got to get your coat,
我们还有好多事要做.
we've got a lot of grand cover today.
开萝尔:我总感觉你想把我累死.
Carol: I do have the feeling that you are going to exhaust me.
麦琪:我怎么老是这样装腔作势呢!
Maggie: Always that cute.
今天我要做的事太多了,
I had so many things that I need to get down today,
但开萝尔的感觉却像是我俩已经成了陌生人,
but carol's feeling like we are turning into strangers,
我怎么可以让她伤心呢?
and how can I break her heart?
杰森:那好吧,不过你该提前告诉我,
Jason: it's nice, but I wish you've told me,
我们已经讲好今天是西沃家的劳动日.
you know we had agreed that today would be a Seavor chore day.
麦琪:我们讲好的?对不起,
Maggie: We did?Oh, I am sorry, it slipped my mind.You are right.
我都不记得了,那好吧,我就不去美发厅了.
I'll cancel my appointment with the salon.
杰森:好的.
Jason: Good.
麦琪:亲爱的,如果这么晚再取消,
Maggie: well, darling, if I cancel this late, I'm going to have to pay anyway.
我还是要付钱的,而且还很贵.
And it's so expensive.
杰森:知道了,你还是去吧.
Jason: Knew, knew, knew.You just go ahead then.
麦琪:对,
Maggie: Yeah, that would be best.
还是这样比较好,我并不是有意留你们干家务劳动活的,
Well, I don't want to keep you man folk from all those sweaty chores you
再见.
have to do.See you.
本:伙计们,我们没办法了.
Ben: Guys, we've been had.
开萝尔:妈妈,我保证会把这时装裙的钱还你的.
Carol: Mom, I promise to pay you back for the stylish dress.
麦琪:不要紧,只要你答应我在公共场合不穿就行.
Maggie: oh, it's ok, just promise you'll never wear it in the public.
宝贝,今天我真是过得愉快.
Sweet heart, I have enjoyed every minute of today.
开萝尔:我也一样,特别是在我看了迈克,本和爸爸因为只能做家务而露出的表情.
Carol: Me too, especially I've looked on Mike, Ben, and Dad's face only keep there
on Chore Day
麦琪:那不好笑.
Maggie: That's not nice.
麦琪:真正有趣的是你爸爸说算知道了,知道了,知道了.你可别告诉他我在笑他的事.
Maggie: Really like to stare at your dad's knew knew knew.You will never tell
your father I was laughing
开萝尔:我保证不会.
Carol: I won't, I promise.
理发师罗德尼:嘿!两位迷人的棕发女郎是谁啊?
Hairdresser Rodney: hey, who these two good looking brown ladies are?
麦琪:哦,你好,罗德尼.
Maggie: Oh, Rodney.Hi.
罗德尼:麦琪,你什么时候才会跟我私奔哪?
Rodney: Maggie, When are you gonna elope off with me, ah?
而且是在大路上,你觉得怎么样?
I mean Ba Bun Ba Ben Ba Bei in the open road.What do you say?
麦琪:等你帮我做完发型后吧!
Maggie: After you do my hair.
开萝尔:妈妈?
Carol: Mom?
罗德尼:妈妈?你说有个女儿,
Rodney: mom?Well, you told me you had a daughter.
但这可是一位成熟的,
But this is a full grown woman with the face in the curves in the whole
亭亭玉立的漂亮小姐,哇!
thing.Wow.
麦琪:这是开萝尔,开萝尔,这是……
Maggie: this is Carol.Carol, this is ....
开萝尔:罗德尼,你好.
Carol: Rodney.Hi...
罗德尼:啊,以前都是谁给你做的发型?
Rodney: aha...Who has been doing your hair, er?
开萝尔:一个叫布伦达的女孩.
Carol: A girl named Brenda.
罗德尼:从现在起,只有我才能碰你的头,
Rodney: look, from now on, nobody, but nobody could touch this head but me.
明白了?
You got that?
开萝尔:好的.
Carol: Yeah.
罗德尼:宝贝.
Rodney: Ba Bei.
罗德尼:麦琪,这次你想做什么发型?
Rodney: Maggie, How about this visit?
你都在这转了一圈!
You take a walk on a while side like that.
麦琪:行了,我也不知道.
Maggie: Oh, Well, I don't know.
罗德尼:以前你不是告诉这发型最流行吗?
Rodney: You tell me that is extremely hot.
麦琪:开萝尔,你看怎么样?
Maggie: Carol, what do you think?
开萝尔:什么怎么样?
Carol: About what?
麦琪:我的发型,你觉得是不是该蓬松一些会更好?
Maggie: My hair.You think I should try to put loose?
开萝尔:哦,你在问我吗?
Carol: Oh, You asking me?
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yes.
开萝尔:哦,叫我怎么讲呢?
Carol: oh, dear.
罗德尼:开萝尔,快告诉你妈妈这发型很好看.
Rodney: Carol, you tell her how delicious it will look
开萝尔:看上去挺……
Carol: Well, when it's proverbially scrumptious.
罗德尼:看!很美吧!
Rodney: see.Yummy.
麦琪:开萝尔,你也这样认为吗?
Maggie: Oh, do you think so, Carol?
罗德尼:麦琪,她讲的就是你,我5分钟后回来.
Rodney: She knows where are she speaks.I will be back in 5.
开萝尔:妈妈,这个男人是在和你调情.
Carol: Mom, Rodney is flirting with you.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Well, yes.
开萝尔:你已经知道了?
Carol: You know it?
麦琪:当然.
Maggie: Of course.
开萝尔:但你都是快要做妈妈的人了.
Carol: But, you are a mother.
麦琪:开萝尔,这也只是偶尔有的事.
Maggie: Carol, it does happen occasionally.
开萝尔:你不是开玩笑吧?那什么时候开始的?
Carol: you are kidding.When?
麦琪:开萝尔,你太幼稚了.
Maggie: Carol, this is silly.
开萝尔:这问题并不幼稚,你把这件事全部都告诉我.
Carol: Well, No, it's not.I want to hear all about it.
麦琪:你是说你想知道那些家伙每次都是怎么跟我调情的?
Maggie: You mean you want to hear about every time some guys innocently flirt with me?
开萝尔:是的,我想知道其中所有的事,所有不肮脏的细节.
Carol: Yeah, I want to hear everything, every juicy disgusting detail.
麦琪:这些都谈不上是肮脏的细节.
Maggie: there is nothing disgusting to tell.
开萝尔:要是爸爸问起,我会把这些一五一十告诉他的.你继续讲你的艳事吧!
Carol: That's what I'll tell Dad if he ever asks.So finish your salty story.
麦琪:我刚刚讲到哪里了?
Maggie: What I have got to left off?
开萝尔:讲到达斯汀·霍夫曼正朝你走来.
Carol: Dustin Hofmann is coming on to you.
麦琪:我并不肯定他是不是正朝我走来,当时他正在新闻发布会上宣传,那时我还在工作.
Maggie: well, I didn't exactly say he is coming on to me.You see, he was promoting the midnight cowboy at this press conference.Just years ago when I was working with news weekly.
开萝尔:达斯汀·霍夫曼?
Carol: Dustin Hofmann?
麦琪:那天我坐在后面的记者席等他,
Maggie: I was sitting at the back accredited for reporters, waiting for him,
接着我起身去洗手间,当我走到大厅走廊的时候,
when I have to go the bathroom.
你知道我亲眼见到谁了吗?
So out on the hallway, who do I run into?Face to face.
开萝尔:达斯汀·霍夫曼.
Carol: Dustin Hofmann
麦琪:是的,他看着我说,
Maggie: Yes, he looked right at me and said:"
新闻发布会现场是不是从这边走?
is it the way to the press conference?"
开萝尔:接着呢?
Carol: And?
麦琪:什么接着?
Maggie: And what?
开萝尔:难道他其他什么都没讲?
Carol: And that's all he said?
麦琪:他还能说什么呢?别忘了当时我们是在办公楼里的过道里.
Maggie: Or what else could he say?We were in office hallway for ......
开萝尔:妈妈,这故事一点也不好听.
Carol: Mom, that's not much of a story.
麦琪:是的,但这就是我全部的艳事.
Maggie: Yeah, but it's all mine
服务生:嘿!女士们.
Waiter: Hey, all ladies.
麦琪:谢谢.
Maggie: thanks.
服务生:这是儿童果汁.
Waiter: The juice is for the kid.
开萝尔:我们就要这个.
Carol: We got it
服务生:那就请慢用.
Waiter: Enjoy it.
开萝尔:妈妈,我想说其实有些事都挺模棱两可的.
Carol: I mean, mom, I have been expecting something really sleazy.
麦琪:模棱两可?
Maggie: Sleazy?
开萝尔:你看,
Carol: Yeah You know, like John Carlen's kinds of stuff.
拿约翰克莉的一些作品来说,
I mean, don't you have something that you never told anyone,
难道说你就没有什么不可告人的事情私人秘密吗?
something you'll be keeping for all these years?
麦琪:当然有了!每个人都是有的.
Maggie: Sure, everybody does.
开萝尔:那你就告诉我吧!好吗?
Carol: Oh, tell me, ok?
麦琪:开萝尔!
Maggie: Carol.
开萝尔:妈妈,就我俩知道,我向你发誓.
Carol: Mom, it's just between us, cross my heart.
麦琪:在你还个婴儿的时候,
Maggie: You know, from you were a baby,
我就在想有一天我和你能象姐妹一样分享秘密.
I used to imagine a day when you and I will be treating secrets like sisters.
开萝尔:希望不是你个人的隐私.
Carol: I hope that's not your secret.
麦琪:不行,好了!就告诉你吧!
Maggie: Oh, no.ok.For your ears only.
开萝尔:好的.
Carol: Of course.
麦琪:两年前,在邻里聚会上,
Maggie: 2 years ago, at that neighborhood picnic,
当时巴德考斯曼后门口企图吻我.
Butt Koosman tried to kiss me at the back porch.
开萝尔:哇!接着呢?
Carol: Wow.What happened?
麦琪:我让他放尊重点,他显得很尴尬,
Maggie: I told him to behave himself.And he got very embarrassed.
并对我道了歉,乞求我别告诉你爸爸,然后就离开了.
And he apologized and begged me not to tell your father and then he threw up.
开萝尔:那你有没有告诉爸爸?
Carol: Did you tell dad?
麦琪:没有,我想没必要让你爸爸烦心,
Maggie: No, there is no reason to get your father upset.
你可是答应过我不会透露一个字的!
And you promise never to say a word.
开萝尔:我不会的.
Carol: Oh, I won't.
麦琪:好了,现在该你讲讲你的秘密了.
Maggie: Ok, it's your turn to show your secrets.
开萝尔:你还记得上个月的星期六吧!
Carol: Remember the Saturday night, last month, when Debbie,
那是我,德宝和雪莉一起去了图书馆,
Shelley and I went to the library,
那晚我们是在德宝家过得夜.
and then we spent the night at the Debbie's house.
麦琪:是嘛!
Maggie: Yeah.
开萝尔:当时我们根本没学习.
Carol: oh, we didn't study at all.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: Yeah?
开萝尔:相反,我们坐火车去了曼哈顿,
Carol: Instead, we took the train into Manhattan,
到一家叫"收获"的俱乐部跳舞.
we went to this Dance club SOHO.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: Yeah?
开萝尔:那地方只让超过21岁的人进去,戴维和雪莉吓得不敢了,
Carol: you have to be 21 to get into this place.
我却坚持下来,然后买通看门人才进去的.
Debbie, Shelley were bent to give up.But I was so cool.I greased the doorman.
麦琪:你还贿赂?
Maggie: Greased?
开萝尔:我贿了20块钱给他,然后我们进去了,
Carol: I slipped him 20 dollars to let us in.We zag zig or what.
你看我们是不是很聪明?太棒了,
Oh, so great.We danced to 4 in the morning with these guys who didn't
我们跟一群不会讲英语的外国人一起跳舞,就这样一直跳到凌晨4点.
even speak English.And then we took the train back and snug into her room
然后坐车回来,趁德宝父母没醒之前,
on sound sleep before her parents ever woke up.
溜进房间睡觉,直到今天还没有人知道那件事.
Until this day, no one is any little awareness.
杰森:他在这里!
Jason: he is here
本:快,快,快!快来吧!
Ben: Go go go.Oh, come on, yeah.
评论员:十……,结束了.
Commentator: ten......It's over.
杰森:这只是玩玩的.
Jason: that's the game.
本:你俩对还欠我50元.
Ben: You both owe me 50 bucks.
杰森:本,是50美分.
Jason: Cents, Ben.50 cents.
本:这么点还不够我花的力气多呢!
Ben: There's no reason be so excited.
开萝尔:妈妈!我们今天玩的正开心,不知西沃家的劳动日进行的怎样了?
Carol: Mom, what a crazy day we have!Hey, what happened on the Seavor's Chore Day?
本:开萝尔,你的头发是怎么回事?
Ben: What's it that kept your head, carol?
杰森:我们答应你们结伴日的要求看来效果不错!开萝尔,
Jason: ah, we decided you two were right, so today is a bonding day.
你看上去真漂亮,简直就是一个大人了!
Carol, you look gorgeous you look so grown-up.
开萝尔:谢谢.
Carol: Thanks.
杰森:你的我不喜欢,麦琪.
Jason: I don't like it. Maggie?
迈克:喂?抱歉,
Mike: Hello?No, sorry, Shelley, Carol can talk.
请你等会,开萝尔刚刚从风口回来.
She has just got out of a wind tunnel.
开萝尔:迈克,我到楼上接,不要忘了把你的电话挂掉.
Carol: Mike, I'll take it upstairs.Be sure to hang it up.
迈克:哦,马上就挂.
Mike: Oh, I do it right now.
麦琪:杰森,我想和你谈谈.
Maggie: Jason, we need to talk.
杰森:哦,抱歉!
Jason: Oh, I am sorry, honey, your hair looks great too.
宝贝,你的头发也很美.不过你有必要在孩子面前露太多嘛?
So you chose to be showing this much neck in front of children?
麦琪:你真会拐弯抹角!
Maggie: Cute.
杰森:也许有一点点吧!
Jason: I thought so.
本:你到底想要怎么样?
Ben: What you'll do this time?
迈克:没什么,只想和你坐一会.
Mike: Nothing, I am sitting here with you.
本:气氛有些不对,不过一般倒霉的都是你.
Ben: Well, trouble is in the air.Usually lams on you
杰森:去了"收获"俱乐部?
Jason: In SOHO?
麦琪:是的!
Maggie: Yes.
杰森:一个人?
Jason: Alone?
麦琪:是的!
Maggie: Yes.
杰森:在那些混乱的酒吧?
Jason: In some city bar?
麦琪:还贿赂了门卫,然后跟一些不会说英语的外国人跳舞.
Maggie: Greasing ports and dance with men who even don't speak English.
杰森:好啊!我得去教育一下她.
Jason: well, I've got to talk to her.
麦琪:杰森,不要去!
Maggie: Oh, Jason, You cannot.
我可答应过她不会告诉任何人的.
I promised her I never tell anyone when she told me.
杰森:当时你已经让我知道了.
Jason: Well, you told me.
麦琪:但是你先答应我说不会对开萝尔讲的呀!
Maggie: But only after you promised never tell Carol what I told you.
杰森:我是不是该闭嘴什么也不讲?
Jason: So am I supposed to do is to just keep my mouth shut and
do nothing
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: That's right.
杰森:但我们不能这样放任开萝尔呀!
Jason: But we cannot let Carol get away with that.
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Jason, if Carol knows that I told you,
要是开萝尔知道我把她的秘密对你说,
she will never speak to me again.
她再也不会跟我讲了.你不是老说我们应该跟孩子们坦率地交流思想吗?
Look, you are the one who always said that we should communicate with
并且要言行一致吗?
our kids be open and honest to speak in the same language.
杰森:但这跟我们才十几岁的女儿和外国男人一起跳舞完全是两码事!
Jason: That's not the case that my teenager daughter is dancing with guys
who speak another language.
开萝尔: 打扰你们一下.
Carol: Excuse me
麦琪:怎么了?
Maggie: What is it?
开萝尔:现在不是时候?
Carol: Is it the bad time?
麦琪:不是的,开萝尔,你有什么事?
Maggie: No, carol, what is it?
开萝尔:你们要是同意,
Carol: If it's all right,
我想去雪莉家让他们看看我的新发型.
can I go over to Shelley's house to show my new hairdo?
杰森:你要到雪莉家去?
Jason: Over to Shelley?
麦琪:我想可以的!你觉得呢?你已经承诺过的.
Maggie: I think that would be just fine.Don't you, Jason, he promised.
杰森:好吧!
Jason: Ok.
开萝尔:哦,太好了!再见,我可能会在那里过夜.
Carol: Oh, great, I will see you then.Oh, I might spend the night too.
杰森:过夜?就像你上次去"收获"俱乐部一样?
Jason: spend the night?Like you did when you took the little trip to SOHO?
开萝尔:你怎么让爸爸知道了?
Carol: You told dad?
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Well.
杰森:她当然应该告诉我,我是你的爸爸呀!
Jason: Of course, she told me.I am your father.
开萝尔:但那是我们之间的秘密呀!
Carol: But it was our secret.
杰森:哦,可是你妈妈觉得我有权利知道.
Jason: Oh, but your mother realized that I have the right to know.
开萝尔:我以为你是信得过的.
Carol: I think I trusted you.
杰森:是呀!开萝尔得明白有时泄密也是必要的,
Jason: Well, she has got to learn that sometime that it's necessary to
不是吗?亲爱的.
break a confidence.Honey?
麦琪:开萝尔,等等.
Maggie: Carol, wait.
开萝尔:什么事?
Carol: What?
麦琪:我想解释一下.
Maggie: I want to explain.
开萝尔:没什么好解释的了,这就是你的错!我真不该将你看成好朋友.
Carol: There is nothing left to explain.It's my fault.I should never have treated
you as my equal
麦琪:开萝尔,要是你还用那种语气跟我讲话,那就回你的房间.
Maggie: Carol, if you are going to take that tone, just go to your room.
开萝尔:好吧!
Carol: Fine, and you said that you dreamed a date on that we'll be treating
刚才你还说你梦想和我能像姐妹一样分享秘密.
secrecy like sisters.Hah!
麦琪:开萝尔,这不公平!
Maggie: Carol, that's not fair.
开萝尔:妈妈,你想要是我把你和巴德考斯曼甚至或者达斯汀霍夫曼的事告诉爸爸,
Carol: Mom, how would you think about if I told dad about the Butts Koosman,
到时不知你会怎么想?
or even the Dustin Hoffmann's affairs, ha?
杰森:什么?麦琪,我没听明白.
Jason: What?Maggie, I don't....
麦琪:杰森,我想你会有充分的理由为自己辩解的,
Maggie: Jason, I know you have good reasons to do you did.
可是现在我没兴致听.
But I am not in the mood to hear it right now.
杰森:那好,那好!
Jason: Fine, fine.
迈克:发生什么事了?好像出大事了.
Mike: How's going?Well, this is big I can feel it.
本:好啊,恶梦开始了.
Ben: Yeah, it is daymare.
迈克:闭嘴!
Mike: Do stop saying that?
本:好吧,不过到底谁是霍夫曼?
Ben: Ok.Who is Hoffmann anyway?
迈克:他是个演员,在他一部电影里他装扮成少妇,
Mike: Some actor guy who is in a movie who is dressed like a chick and
然后和男人接吻.
kiss some guy.
本:他真是比我想象的还要差劲.
Ben: He was more showy than I thought.
麦琪:别打扰我!
Maggie: Excuse me.
杰森:对不起!
Jason: Excuse me.
麦琪:今天不行.
Maggie: Not today
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, I know you are upset.
我知道你现在很生气,但是你也要明白我作为一个父亲的责任,
I know you also understand my responsibility as parent supersedes my
这远远大于保密的意义.
obligation to keep confidence.
麦琪:当然我明白!
Maggie: Of course I do
杰森:很好,你开始理解了.
Jason: Well, good, and this is progress.
麦琪:我觉得你处理这件事的方式有点太过……
Maggie: And I know that you understand your handling the situation was
completely .......
杰森:那向你道歉,我当时太过情绪化了,
Jason: Ok, I am sorry, I am sorry.My emotions got the best of me.
不过我想你是能理解我的.
I am sure you can understand that.
麦琪:我当然理解.
Maggie: I certainly can
杰森:那太好了!
Jason: Good.
麦琪:这是因为现在也有种情绪困扰着我.迈克,
Maggie: Because right now, my emotions have the best of me.
开萝尔,本过来晚饭了.
Mike, Carol, Ben, Dinner......
本:该吃饭了!
Ben: It's about the time.
麦琪:迈克,你怎么不吃啊?
Maggie: Mike, why aren't you eating?
迈克:哦,没什么!
Mike: oh, no reason.
本:他是担心你们觉得他才是所有麻烦的制造者.
Ben: He is scared that you guys are going to find out that he is
behind the all these trouble
本:本,这件事和迈克无关!
Jason: Ben, it doesn't concern Mike.
迈克:看看,我都说了这不关我的事.
Mike: Say, I told you.
本:那你就等着吧!
Ben: That's me that will get you later.
开萝尔:坐这里可以,母亲,但我不想吃.
Carol: I sit, but I won't eat.Mother
麦琪:母亲?她居然叫我母亲.
Maggie: Mother?She called me mother.
杰森:麦琪,她不是那意思.
Jason: Maggie, she doesn't mean that.
麦琪:看来坐这里的并不她一个人口是心非的.
Maggie: So she is not the only person at the table who says things they
don't mean?
杰森:好了,看来我们有必要开个家庭会议了!
Jason: Ok, I think it's the time we have a family talk about this.
迈克:那我先走.
Mike: I should go.
开萝尔:别担心,迈克,这次是我要挨批评了.
Carol: Don't worry, Mike.I am the one who is going to be grounded.
迈克:那我就留下.
Mike: I should stay.
杰森:迈克,这不关你的事,你可以出去了.
Jason: Mike, it doesn't concern you.
迈克:你不是说是家庭会议吗?
Mike: Well, you said we should have a family talk.
我想我是这家的一份子.
I believe I am part of the family.
麦琪:走开,迈克,把本也带走.
Maggie: Leave, Mike.And take Ben with you.
本:真是好球呀!迈克,是你害我被赶出这个家的.
Ben: Good goal, Mike, you just keep me kicked out of the family too.
杰森:开萝尔,我们需要谈谈你母亲之所以有……,
Jason: What we need to talk about is why your mother had the right er...
嗯!
What we need to talk about is why your mother had the right to tell me
我们需要谈谈你妈妈为什么具有告诉我你的事的权利,还有我有权管那事的原因.
what you did, and why I had the right to act on that information.
迈克:打扰一下,请你们说清楚一点,这件事真的和我无关吗?
Mike: Ha ha ha Excuse me.Just be one hundred percent clear that this thing
has nothing to do with me, whatsoever
杰森:出去,迈克.
Jason: Get out, Mike
开萝尔:也许我也该走了!
Carol: May I be excused too?
杰森:你不能走!
Jason: No, you may not.
开萝尔,
Carol, your mother had a right,
你妈妈有权也有义务把你做的事告诉我.
she knows she had the obligation to tell me what you did.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: That's right.
开萝尔:不,你没有,你答应我不会说出去的.
Carol: No, not when you promised not to.
杰森:你爸爸的意思是我们可是你的父母呀!
Jason: What your father is saying is that sweet heart, we are the parents.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:我们是为你着想.
Maggie: We were responsible for you.
杰森:是的.
Jason: Yes
麦琪:如果你爸爸侵犯了我的隐私,
Maggie: It'll be a different matter,
那就不同了!
say if your father violates my confidence.
杰森:的确如此!
Jason: Exactly, oh, no
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: Yes.
杰森:不是的.
Jason: no
麦琪:是这样的.
Maggie: Yes.
开萝尔:我忙着呢!
Carol: I am busy.
杰森:开萝尔,
Jason: Carol, it's your father.I want to apologize for grounding you.
我是爸爸.我想为我对你的不公到道歉,
Make I treat you unfairly, make it up to you,
我给你买辆新车当赔礼吧!
I want to buy you a new car.
开萝尔:哦!快进来,快进来!
Carol: Oh, Come in, come in.
杰森:我骗你的,我不是真的来道歉的.
Jason: I was lying.I am not really here to apologize at all.
开萝尔:那我的新车呢?
Carol: What about the new car?
杰森:也是骗你的.
Jason: Also a lie.
杰森:我只是想让你也感受一下你信任的人对你撒谎的感觉.
Jason: I just want you to feel only for a moment what was like when somebody
you trust lies to you.
开萝尔:给我买旧车也行!
Carol: What about used car?
杰森:开萝尔,
Jason: Carol, I am talking about the lie you told about spending the night
我想说说你当时怎么骗我们你去德宝家过夜的.
at Debbie's.
开萝尔:就像妈妈骗我一样.
Carol: Like mom has lied to me.
杰森:看来你是不会忘记你妈妈把你的秘密告诉我的事了!
Jason: it's just you won't get off these things about your mom telling
me what you did, will you?
开萝尔:要是我把她那些丑事告诉你,那怕是一点点暗示,
Carol: I just know that mom will be real mad if I told you even a
我想她也会发疯的.
hint of those disgusting things she told me about.
杰森:哈哈,那不一样,她说什么啦?不,不!我对此不感兴趣,即使你有告诉我的权利.
Jason: Ha.....that's different.What did she say?No, no, don't mind.I am not
interested.What even you're right for me to know
开萝尔:怎么了?
Carol: What's wrong?
杰森:没什么!
Jason: Oh, nothing.
开萝尔:爸爸,哪里痛?
Carol: Dad, you are paining.
杰森:不,不!我很好!
Jason: No, no, I am fine, I am great.
开萝尔:不,你有事!
Carol: No, you are not.
杰森:我很好,我只是不想让别人知道!
Jason: I am fine, I just don't want anybody to know it.
开萝尔:爸爸,我保证不会跟别人讲的!
Carol: Dad, I promise that I won't say a word.
杰森:好吧,就让你知道吧,我得了胃溃疡.
Jason: Well, there is a chance, a chance of developing an ulcer.
开萝尔:很严重吗?
Carol: Serious?
杰森:是的,要是心情不好胃就很难受.
Jason: Well, it could be if I get agitated or upset.
开萝尔:那就把迈克撵出去吧!
Carol: Well, Mike is just going to move out.
杰森:这是个好提议.
Jason: It's very funny that.
开萝尔:爸爸?
Carol: Dad?
杰森:我过段时间再谈,现在我要去办公室休息一下.
Jason: We are going to talk more about this later.I am just going to
lay in office for a rest
开萝尔:不!
Carol: Oh, no.
杰森:要是这有评委的话,我都可以拿到艾美奖.
Jason: If there is any justice at all, I should get an Ammi for that.
开萝尔:妈妈.
Carol: Mom.
麦琪:开萝尔.
Maggie: Carol.
开萝尔和麦琪:我想和你谈谈.
Carol& Maggie: I need to talk to you.
开萝尔和麦琪:你先讲!
Carol& Maggie: You first.
开萝尔和麦琪:好的!
Carol& Maggie: All right.
开萝尔和麦琪:还是你先讲吧!
Carol& Maggie: After you.
麦琪:亲爱的,真是抱歉,我真不该食言把你的秘密告诉你爸爸.
Maggie: Oh, honey, I am sorry.I broke my word to you and told your father...
开萝尔:妈妈,这无所谓了!
Carol: Mom, I don't care about that.
麦琪:你不在乎了?
Maggie: You don't?
开萝尔:是的,你看到爸爸了吗?他好像不舒服.
Carol: No.Have you seen dad?He is in pain.
麦琪:他一看到我们闹矛盾就会装病的.
Maggie: He was always like that when we have been in a fight.
开萝尔:不是的,他真的不舒服,他告诉我的.
Carol: No, he is in pain.He told me.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
开萝尔:是胃溃疡,他不想让你担心.
Carol: It's an ulcer.He didn't want to worry you.
麦琪:杰森·罗兰度·西沃!
Maggie: Jason, Rolando Seavor.
开萝尔:现在他在他办公室.
Carol: He is in his office.
本:迈克,他们快要开战了!
Ben: It's getting closer, Mike.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
本:世界末日来了!
Ben: The end of the world?
麦琪:杰森,你为什么不告诉我?
Maggie: Jason, Why didn't you tell me?
杰森:四分十五秒,这成绩不错.
Jason: 4 minutes 15 seconds, not bad.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:开萝尔,我想一定有人想加入到我们的谈话中.
Jason: Oh, I thought, somebody else should be included in this conversation.Well, Carol
开萝尔:爸爸,我才不管你是不是疯了.
Carol: Dad, I don't care if you get mad or not.
麦琪:杰森,你的胃溃疡是怎么回事?
Maggie: Jason, What is this about?The ulcer?
杰森:开萝尔,你妈妈好像知道了你我间的秘密,
Jason: Carol, Your mother seems to know the thing only you and I are supposed
这是怎么回事?
to know.How could this be?
开萝尔:我们很担心你的健康问题,爸爸.
Carol: What we worry about is how's your seemingly, dad.
杰森:我很好!
Jason: Run-down.
麦琪:我怎么知道你的病这并不重要.
Maggie: It doesn't matter about how I found out this ulcer business.
杰森:这很重要!
Jason: But it does matter.
开萝尔:爸爸,妈妈有权知道.
Carol: Dad, mom had the right to know.
杰森:那么说你是泄密了?
Jason: So it's ok to violate confidence?
开萝尔:那不重要!重要的是我们很担心你的健康,
Carol: that's not the point, the point is that we are worried about you.
你的健康更重要.
That's more important.
麦琪:是的.
Maggie: That's right.
杰森:哦!
Jason: Oh......!!
杰森:好吧!我肯定你俩现在有话要说.
Jason: Well, I am sure you two have things to talk about.
即使没有,我也得块离开,以免你们拿东西砸我.
Even If you don't, I am leaving now before you throw something at me.
杰森:我最讨厌他这样!
Jason: I hate what he does that.
开萝尔:我也一样.
Carol: Me too.
麦琪:他真是自以为是呀!当这很重要.
Maggie: He gets so smug."Oh, but it does matter."
开萝尔:我不想笑,我还在生你的气呢!
Carol: I don't want to laugh, I am still mad at you.
麦琪:宝贝,我为告诉你爸爸你的秘密向你道歉!
Maggie: I am sorry, sweetheart.I am sorry that I told your father.
当你说我能怎么办?谁叫我是你妈妈呢!
But what choice did I have?I am your mother.
开萝尔:在告诉你之前,
Carol: Yeah, I should remember that before I open my mouth.
我真是应该好好考虑一下的.
I think what I could have told you.
麦琪:开萝尔?
Maggie: Carol?
开萝尔:你是对的.
Carol: You are right.
麦琪:今天我们过得真是开心呀!
Maggie: We did have a funny day.
开萝尔:是啊!遗憾的是我们以后不可能再那样谈心了.
Carol: Yeah, the shame is we will never be able to talk like that again.
麦琪:还会的,宝贝!等你再大一些,比如考上了大学,住进了陌生的宿舍.另外,等你经历了嘈杂和疯狂的大学生活,接着第一次住进公寓后,到时我们一边吃午餐,一边听你谈论你的男友和其他一些好笑的事情,然后就是你结婚后.
Maggie: oh, Shall we?Well, Sweetheart?When you get a little bit older, say when
you are in college maybe you live in a cold dorm.On the other hand
college is such a noisy crazy drive of period, I know.After college, when you
move into your first apartment, well, you can make lunch and you tell me all
the men you are dating will be crazy.After you are married
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
麦琪:然后生了小孩.
Maggie: And have babies.
开萝尔:小孩?
Carol: Baby?
麦琪:两个小孩也有可能.宝贝,
Maggie: Maybe two.Honey, we have so much in common.
我们的共同点太多了,这就是女人跟女人的默契.
We'll have a real woman to woman bargaining.
当你回家过圣诞节的时候,等把孙子们都安排去睡觉后,
And when you come home for Xmas, we can sit by the fire, chat,
我们就可以坐在火炉边聊聊.开萝尔:是你的外孙还是我的?
have the grandchildren and put them to bed.
00:22:57,100
Carol: Are these your grandchildren or mine?